Are you planning a trip to Europe next
year?
My question is, is Europe expensive?
Or is it because our planning is wrong?
My real answer is that Europe is not
expensive.
If we plan well, we can plan a
budget-friendly trip to Europe.
If you have seen my previous videos on
Switzerland, Italy and other destinations, you will realise
that I have planned a lot of budget
trips to Europe.
I have been travelling for last 10 years
to various European destinations and covered almost 10
countries because I do a slow-paced travel.
Friends, I am Heenasha.
In today's video, we will talk about the
mistakes I made in the past year which
should not be repeated and what I learnt
from it.
And this is what I am going to
share with you today.
So, today I will share my biggest wins
and biggest regrets of the past year.
I mean, they are not really regrets.
But yeah, I did end up making some
mistakes.
And I don't want you all to repeat
these mistakes.
So, today I will share with you what
you can do right.
So that you can save thousands of rupees
for your next Europe trip.
Whenever we think about Europe, we only think
about cities.
You have to cover Venice, Rome, Milan, Vienna,
Prague, Interlaken, Zurich.
You know, you only focus on cities.
Not you.
In fact, I used to focus on the
same things.
But eventually, I realised that only cities are
not the charm of Europe.
More than cities, village travel and small towns
are the places where you get to enjoy
and experience Europe.
If I talk about last year, we went
to Europe in March and May.
In March, we went to Vienna and Prague.
And in May, we did a trip to
beautiful European Alpine towns.
You must have seen how beautiful and relaxed
this trip was in my last video.
And as I have told you earlier also
in the video, it was one of our
most cherished destinations so far.
So, what mistakes did we make?
So, let's start with the Vienna and Prague
trip.
In Vienna, we had about three days.
But we spent a lot of time exploring
the cities.
But then, on the third day, I realised
that there is a town called Melk.
It is nearby.
By train, it was about an hour's distance.
So, we had already taken the pass.
We took an extra ticket and went to
Melk.
And it was a beautiful, serene town.
And you can see the videos, the photos
on the screen.
And you can guess.
So, what I learnt from my mistakes?
You should not only explore the cities but
also the villages.
And what happened in Prague?
We were in Prague for 2-3 days.
And on the first day, we woke up
relaxed and had breakfast.
And on 10 o'clock, we reached Old
Town Square.
And by that time, it was so crowded.
Though, it was the month of March.
And still, there were a lot of crowds.
So, if you want to take a photo,
you can't take a solo photo.
Because there are a lot of tourist crowds
right next to you.
And you can go to any destination.
We went to Charles Bridge.
And Charles Bridge was teeming with people.
It was so crowded that we got separated.
My husband was somewhere else.
My daughter was somewhere else.
And I was somewhere else.
So, we coordinated on the phone and got
along.
So, please be careful.
Prague is beautiful.
But, what did we do the next day?
Early morning, at 6 o'clock.
Yes, friends.
If you want to avoid crowds and see
the place properly, then you have to do
this.
So, next day, early morning, at 6 o
'clock, we woke up.
And directly, we went to Old Town.
Luckily, our apartment was just 5 minutes walking
distance from Old Town.
And it was very easy.
The walks were beautiful.
We woke up and left.
We took a lot of photos.
We saw a lot of monuments.
And we walked till the next destination.
We saw the dancing house.
And then we came back.
After that, we had breakfast.
So, which saved us a lot of hassle
from the crowds.
And it was beautiful cold March morning.
Not very cold, of course.
But, very pleasantly cold.
We enjoyed the walk.
We enjoyed the destination.
So, what we learnt is basically, get up
early, go to the destination.
You have to do the same thing in
Venice.
Venice is again a crowded city.
Start early, as early as 6 am.
Yes, enjoy the sunrise.
You know, you will avoid the crowds.
And you will really enjoy all the views
around you.
So, do that.
Same thing in Rome.
Rome is again a very very crowded city.
As far as tourists are concerned, we were
there in the month of March last year.
And again, there is not a single photograph
in which you won't get a crowd.
We tried a lot of solo photographs.
But, that was not possible.
You can see the pictures on the screen.
And then, finally next day, what we did
is 6 am.
Correct.
We got up at 6 am.
We explored whatever destinations we wanted.
And then, after exploring a little bit, we
went in for our breakfast.
What I am telling you is related to
currency.
So, last year, when we went from Switzerland
to Italy.
And then we had some Swiss francs left
on us.
In Venice, we didn't realize that the currency
we were exchanging, we didn't see the commissions
there.
And it was a very big mistake.
So, whatever we gave, we got almost 40
% commission.
And we got the rest of the money
in Euros.
And we really regretted our decision that why
didn't we check the commissions.
So, please, I would like to tell you
that if you are exchanging currency, then first
of all, check the commissions.
Yeah, this happened with us because we generally
don't exchange the currency.
And that's why we didn't realize.
Generally, we always use a credit card.
And whatever cash we take from here, we
use that.
So, this was almost like a first time
where we exchanged the Swiss francs for Euros.
And we ended up suffering huge loss.
So, please be careful to check the exchange
rates.
And especially the commission rates if you are
doing any kind of currency exchange.
Now, I am going to share a few
more of my mistakes with you.
Which you should not repeat.
So, if you don't do it, again, you
will save thousands of rupees.
So, let me tell you, when I was
planning a trip to Italy last year.
You know, we were planning to go from
one city to another.
And we were supposed to take trains.
So, at that time, I was almost going
to book the tickets on Train Italia.
But then I realized that Italo is also
there.
Which is another provider there.
And then I did a lot of research.
And on Reddit and TripAdvisor, I read what
people have written about Italo.
And that helped me do two things.
One, I didn't book an expensive train to
Italy.
Secondly, first of all, I subscribed to Italo.
So, when you go to their website and
subscribe to their newsletter, what happens?
In your inbox, 70% off, 50%
off, 30% off, 1 for 1 free.
All these coupons come.
So, when you want to book actual tickets,
you can use these coupon codes.
And you can book tickets for almost 50%,
70% off on Italo.
And I did that.
Trust me, I got the tickets at a
very, very low cost.
For three offers.
You know, imagine 30% off, 50%
off.
And these are genuine offers.
Friends, I have actually used these offers.
And that's why I can tell you.
Even now, Italo mails keep coming to my
inbox.
I keep getting offers.
So, what happens is, I do not unsubscribe.
I keep the newsletters subscribed.
Similarly, if you have seen my Switzerland video,
then I have told you first of all.
Please subscribe to the newsletters of various Swiss
websites.
Go to sbb.ch and subscribe to their
newsletter.
Such good offers come.
And one more offer that I used in
Switzerland.
I have also told you about that in
my previous videos.
How did we reach Locarno?
How did I get free tickets from Geneva
to Locarno?
These tickets are very, very expensive.
You all know by now that the trip
to Switzerland is very expensive.
There is one big reason.
The value of the rupee is decreasing.
And the value of the Swiss franc is
increasing.
So, because of that, the trip to Switzerland
becomes very expensive.
And if you use these small tips that
I am giving you.
Then your trip can be very beneficial.
It can be in the budget.
You can get a lot of savings from
these discounts.
So, please subscribe to various newsletters.
Again, a very, very important tip when you
are planning your trip.
Specially to Switzerland.
If you are going to do mountain excursions.
If you are going to go to Jungfraujoch.
Then please do not buy the tickets of
Jungfraujoch in advance.
The tickets of Jungfraujoch are very expensive.
And if you have already bought the tickets
of a particular date.
And if that day it is raining.
Then whatever you have spent can go to
waste.
Even if you go up, you will only
see clouds and fog.
Whatever views you wanted to go to enjoy.
You will not be able to see that.
So, my request and my suggestion would be.
Whenever you go to Switzerland.
You see the weather of that day.
And decide after seeing the weather.
Whether you want to do a mountain excursion
or not.
Only if it is nice clear weather.
Please go to the mountain excursions.
Otherwise, your mountain excursions will not be useful
at all.
You will only see fog and clouds.
Friends, if you are planning a Norway trip.
Then definitely you must have seen the Norway
in a nutshell trip.
You must have seen in many videos.
How Norway is focused on a nutshell.
And more or less.
People purchase the readymade package of Norway in
a nutshell.
But I didn't do that.
We had gone to Norway a couple of
years back.
And at that time, I myself researched and
planned the Norway in a nutshell trip.
And it was really really.
Turned out to be very beautiful.
Not only that.
Where we had to stay overnight.
We stayed there.
So, my trip from Oslo to Bergen.
In which we did not just travel by
train.
We travelled by train.
Then the wooden train.
Special.
Plum Railways.
We travelled on that.
We travelled on Sognefjord.
By ship.
It was really nice.
And then we reached Bergen.
So, the whole trip was completely planned by
me.
And we ended up saving thousands of rupees.
So, I would like to tell you the
same thing.
Do not purchase readymade packages.
If you do research yourself.
Then at a very reasonable price.
You can get better trips than the already
readymade trips.
And yes.
In case if you don't have time to
plan this trip.
Then you can definitely write to me at
my email id.
I have mentioned it in the description box.
I will definitely help you plan your trips.
Because I have been doing it for many
customers.
Many viewers.
And they have had really good trips so
far.
So, please do write to me.
If you want me to plan your trip.
In such a customized manner.
And definitely.
Again, I reiterate.
Please go for slow travel now.
Do not rush.
10 countries in 10 days.
5 countries in 10 days.
You have to go to Amsterdam.
You have to go to Paris.
You have to go to Switzerland.
You have to go to Italy.
In just one trip.
I would say no.
Please do not do it.
You know.
It is like.
There is a buffet.
And you have to eat everything.
Little by little.
You know.
Of every dish.
You are tasting.
But.
You are not able to enjoy any dish
properly.
So, in case of Europe.
Please do not do a rush trip.
Do a slow pace.
Enjoying trip.
And do not just concentrate on cities.
Please do concentrate on the villages.
The small towns.
The border towns also.
Like I told you in my last video.
About Shimni.
How did we go from Shimni to Vellorecini.
Vellorecini is just 2 km away from Switzerland.
And just like Switzerland.
The same atmosphere.
And there was no one else.
It was just us.
Enjoying the whole place.
So, you know.
When you do such things.
The actual enjoyment.
The actual memories.
Are made from this kind of slow travel.
So, for next year.
I would request you.
If you are planning a Europe trip.
So, please focus on.
Less countries.
Slow travel.
And do some self research.
And do some planning.
Your trip will be great.
And in a budget.
Europe is not expensive.
But due to wrong planning.
We always find Europe expensive.
There are quite a lot of hacks.
That you can use.
The tips videos of my Europe trip.
2 videos I have uploaded.
Long back.
Please watch them.
I have given you such good tips.
That your trip can be on a budget.
So, plan a beautiful budget trip to Europe.
Watch this channel.
This is a channel which gives you honest
advice.
Honest.
The mistakes I have made.
And how I have rectified them.
How I plan my Europe trips.
Almost every year.
And twice in a year also.
You can learn from my mistakes.
So that your trip is great.
And I would like to wish you all.
A very happy new year.
Stay safe.
Travel safe. (Transcribed by TurboScribe.ai.)